Finding Aids to Personal Papers and Special Collections in the VMFA Archives Leslie Cheek, Jr. Personal Papers, 1931-1993 SC-02
VMFA Archives
- Series 1: Skylark Farm, 1966-1992; SC-02-01; 197 folders;; 2 items
  - Beacon Hill Property, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 169)
  - News release, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 170)
  - Correspondence with children regarding gift of Skylark, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 171)
  - Expenses-preparing Skylark for sale or gift, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 172)
  - Cancelled checks to substantiate gift, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 173)
  - Personal letters regarding gift to Washington and Lee, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 174)
  - Hans P. Ziegler, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 175)
  - Washington and Lee University-R.L. Huntley, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 176)
  - J. Quincy Hunsicker, 3rd, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 177)
  - R.S. Keefe, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 178)
  - Tax info-Skylark, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 179)
  - Skylark-1977 income tax data (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 180)
  - Income tax data, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 181)
  - Work sheets, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 182)
  - Interest statements, dividends, refund, tax bills-real estate/personal property, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 183)
  - Gasoline tax, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 184)
  - Telephone tax, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 185)
  - Postage and secretarial, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 186)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 187)
  - Dues and subscriptions, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 188)
  - Stationary and supplies, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 189)
  - Business expenses, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 190)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Lowell Humphreys, 1971-1975 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 191)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Lowell Humphreys, 1973 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 192)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Lowell Humphreys, 1976-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 193)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Lowell Humphreys, 1984-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 194)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Harry Farber, farm manager, Apr. 1967-Mar. 1972 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 195)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence: Harry Farber, 1967-1974 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 196)
  - RESTRICTED: Employee correspondence: Luther Cash, 1975 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 197)
  - "Sign No. One, Skylark Farm," drawing by Leslie Cheek, Dec. 1969 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
  - "Christmas Tree Plantation Layout = 4949 Trees - Plan of Plantation Number One = 1349 Trees," drawing by Leslie Cheek of Skylark Farm, July 1967 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
- Series 2: "Living by Design" and "Cheek and The Arts", 1945-1989; SC-02-02; 83 folders;; 1 item
  This series is comprised of correspondence, interviews, and exhibition details related to the 1985 publication of "Living by Design: Leslie Cheek and the Arts," which was written by Parke Rouse, Jr. and researched by K. Richmond Temple. The photobiography was released at the same time that a corresponding exhibition entitled "Cheek and the Arts" opened at the Muscarelle Museum of Art in December 1985.
  - Q and A, Leslie Cheek Jr. to Elizabeth for volume one, 1945-1982 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 198)
  - Tapes-original: transcripts of taped interviews with various people prior to photobiography number one, includes index to tapes, 1982-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 199)
  - Travel art-Virginia Museum, correspondence with Paul Perrot, photographs, 1986-1988 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 200)
  - Travel art-Washington and Lee, 1985-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 201)
  - Travel art-Century Club, 1986-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 202)
  - Travel art-Stratford, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 203)
  - Travel art-Asheville, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 204)
  - Travel art-Cheekwood, undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 205)
  - Travel art show schedule: inventory list of objects, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 206)
  - Traveling portion-"Cheek and The Arts", undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 207)
  - Travel art-University of Richmond, undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 208)
  - Cheek's notes for biography: outline sketch, 1983 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 209)
  - Biography cost-financial arrangement, 1984-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 210)
  - Art exhibition-Stratford, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 211)
  - "Cheek and The Arts"-organization: Muscarelle exhibition, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 212)
  - Book Reviews: excerpts from "Time" and "Harvard" magazines, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 213)
  - 5 December exhibition, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 214)
  - "Cheek and The Arts"-other U.S. galleries, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 215)
  - Bills-"Cheek and The Arts", undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 216)
  - Exhibition transportation, 1985-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 217)
  - Slide show notes, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 218)
  - Preview letters, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 219)
  - Muriel Christison, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 220)
  - Westcott Cunningham, 1985-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 221)
  - Ray Geary, 1983-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 222)
  - Art exhibition correspondence-general, 1983-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 223)
  - General correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 224)
  - Mark Johnson, 1985-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 225)
  - Glen Lowry, 1983-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 226)
  - Art exhibition-Bill Ryan, 1983-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 227)
  - Pinkney Near, 1983-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 228)
  - Legal costs: Buck Pennington, Ron Jennings MISSING, 1983-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 229)
  - Correspondence: biographical data, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 230)
  - Biography correspondence current: monthly reports and personal letters to Leslie Cheek's children, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 231)
  - Title page, undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 232)
  - Correspondence current, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 233)
  - Responses to biography questionnaire, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 234)
  - Publicity, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 235)
  - Biography correspondence-general current, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 236)
  - Correspondence non-current, undated (Box SC-02 Box 5, Folder Folder 237)
  - Biography-general correspondence A-O, 1984-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 238)
  - Biography-general correspondence P-Z, 1984-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 239)
  - Acknowledgements, bibliography, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 240)
  - Correspondence-luncheons, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 241)
  - Correspondence-Alumni Society, 1984-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 242)
  - Correspondence-Society of the Alumni, 1984-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 243)
  - Biography-Helen Dohn, 1984-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 244)
  - Biography-Ray Geary, 1984-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 245)
  - Biography-John Canaday, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 246)
  - Biography-Ron Jennings, 1982 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 247)
  - Biography-Elizabeth Morgan, 1978-1983 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 248)
  - Biography-Parke Rouse, old (before 1985), 1983-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 249)
  - Biography-Parke Rouse, 1956-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 250)
  - Correspondence-questions to answers, A-K: includes correspondence with Bernard Von Bothmer, Alistair Cook and Vincent Bowditch, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 251)
  - Correspondence-questions to answers, L-Z: includes correspondence with Sherman Lee, Thomas Messer, Roger Mudd and Vincent Price, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 252)
  - Biography-John Walker: includes John Walker's forward to biography, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 253)
  - Financial-Pat Foran: invoices for salaries and publications, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 254)
  - Biography costs-miscellaneous, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 255)
  - Biography costs-Richmond account, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 256)
  - Biography costs-fund WandM, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 257)
  - Biography costs-office, postage, publication, typing service, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 258)
  - Biography costs-Elizabeth Morgan, 1983 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 259)
  - Biography costs-photography, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 260)
  - Museum presidents, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 261)
  - Leslie Cheek's chronology: biographical data, resume, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 262)
  - Biography-Richmond Temple, 1983-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 263)
  - Biography outline, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 264)
  - Biography-family: miscellaneous family notes, 1945 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 265)
  - Biography costs-Helen Dohn, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 266)
  - Biography costs-Parke Rouse, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 267)
  - Salary-Ray Geary, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 268)
  - Biography costs-salary, Richmond Temple, 1984-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 269)
  - Muscarelle plans, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 270)
  - Luncheon-Sydnor: exhibition event, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 271)
  - Invitation letter "Cheek and The Arts", Dec. 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 272)
  - Correspondence regarding review, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 273)
  - Newspaper clips regarding exhibition, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 274)
  - Muscarelle Museum Exhibit, 1984-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 275)
  - Muscarelle Celebration, 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 276)
  - "Cheek and the Arts" - Slide Presentation, undated (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 277)
  - "Cheek and the Arts" - Century Club Exhibition, 1986-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 278)
  - "Living by Design" - Temple, etc., 1988-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 6, Folder Folder 279)
  - RESTRICTED: Transcripts-Richmond Temple interviews. Some interviews marked confidential., 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 280)
  - "New exhibit, book trace Leslie Cheek's career," RTD clipping, Dec. 1985 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
- Series 3: "Designing for the Arts", 1984-1991; SC-02-03; 60 folders
  This series is comprised of correspondence, drafts, and financial details related to the 1990 publication of "Designing for the Arts: Environments by Leslie Cheek," which was written by K. Richmond Temple. It was designed as a photo essay, and served as volume two to the previously published "Living by Design" in 1985.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence: family connection with restoration of Parthenon (Tennessee) and other historic buildings, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 281)
  - Memos to Richmond Temple: "Designing for the Arts" project, 1988-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 282)
  - Pie Friendly's writings: early research for biography, 1987 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 283)
  - Outline: chronology and interviews for biography, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 284)
  - Introduction and Chapter 1, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 285)
  - Chapter Two draft, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 286)
  - Chapter Four draft, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 287)
  - Chapter Five draft, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 288)
  - Chapter Six draft, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 289)
  - Chapter Seven draft, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 290)
  - Settings for the arts: manuscript revisions, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 291)
  - Autobiography: Cheek notes and chronology, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 292)
  - Galley-Richmond Temple: galley proofs, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 293)
  - Book party notes, 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 294)
  - List receiving books Vol. 1, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 295)
  - Vol. II "Designing For The Arts" sent out, 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 296)
  - Afterword/foreword Vol. II: printers proofs, copies of dust jacket, letter from J. Carter Brown, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 297)
  - Afterword/foreword Vol. II: Richmond Temple and Guy Friddell, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 298)
  - Cheek Chronology (1908-1981) and resume, undated (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 299)
  - Interviews-"Designing For The Arts", 1987 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 300)
  - Correspondence Robert W. Stewart, AIA and Nancy Jordan Tenant for Vol. II, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 301)
  - Accounts for "Designing for the Arts": ledger accounts, 1987-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 302)
  - Biography sent A-G, 1985-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 303)
  - Biography sent H-L, 1985-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 304)
  - Biography sent M-R, 1985-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 305)
  - Biography sent S-Z, 1985-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 306)
  - Vol. I thank you's A-L, 1985-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 307)
  - Vol. I thank you's M-Z, 1987-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 308)
  - Vol. II thank you's, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 309)
  - Format and outlines for Vol. II: schedules, outlines and proposed interviews, 1986-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 310)
  - Correspondence with Betty Stacy: research questions, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 311)
  - Correspondence: search for a publisher of Book II, 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 312)
  - Contract-publisher and correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 313)
  - Contract Vol. II-Richmond Temple and correspondence, 32629 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 314)
  - Vol. II correspondence-Ray Geary, Geary and Flynn Design Inc., 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 315)
  - Debut Party Vol. II, Apr. 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 316)
  - Library of Congress and ISBN forms for Vol. II, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 317)
  - Index For Vol. II, undated (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 318)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-miscellaneous Virginia subjects, 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 319)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-Russell Lynes, interviews and foreword for biography, 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 320)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-Alumni Society of WandM, 1986-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 321)
  - Correspondence-Carter Brown, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 322)
  - Carter Brown's thesis on Virginia Museum, undated (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 323)
  - Letters for information-biography: background material from classmates, family, friends and associates, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 324)
  - Previews-Vol. II, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 325)
  - Vol. II-Debut: announcements, plans, 1990-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 326)
  - Costs-"Designing For The Arts" Fund-correspondence with Society of the Alumni, WandM, 1988-1992 (Box SC-02 Box 7, Folder Folder 327)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-Richmond Temple, 1989-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 328)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-Richmond Temple, 1984-1988 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 329)
  - Correspondence Vol. II-Pie Friendly, 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 330)
  - Correspondence-Ray Geary and Geary, Flynn and Crane Inc., 1986-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 331)
  - Photography Vol. II: New York trip, Richmond Temple and Century Associates, Dec. 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 332)
  - Financial arrangement: correspondence with WandM Society of the Alumni, 1984-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 333)
  - Bills-miscellaneous invoices, 1988-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 334)
  - Bills-Raymond Geary, invoices Geary, Flynn Crane, Inc., 1988-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 335)
  - Bills-costs, "Designing for The Arts" account sheets, 1987-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 336)
  - Bills-Richmond Temple salary and expenses, 1988-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 337)
  - Correspondence-miscellaneous, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 338)
  - "Designing for the Arts", 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 339)
- Series 4: Personal Files, 1934-1992; SC-02-04; 211 folders;; 25 items
  This series is mainly comprised of correspondence related to a myriad of activities and projects that Cheek took on throughout his career and during his retirement. There is a considerable amount of material created during his tenure as Director of the VMFA. This series also contains oversized materials, including many drawings done by Cheek while in school in the 1930s and after, as well as photographs, mounted clippings, and some bound volumes and drawings.
  - American Clan Leslie Society, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 340)
  - 4 Homes, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 341)
  - Harvard College Overseers, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 342)
  - Woodberry Forest - J. Carter Walker Memorial Center Dedication, 1966 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 343)
  - Ross Valentine Articles, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 344)
  - Richmond News-Leader Article on Cheek by Guy Friddell, 1979 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 345)
  - Century Club - George Dandridge Gibson, 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 346)
  - Voice of the People from Robert Hiedemann, 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 347)
  - Transcriptions of Interviews with Cheek, 1964-1982 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 348)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 349)
  - Roanoke College, 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 350)
  - William Hodges Baker Thesis - Origin and Early Development of the Virginia Museum Theatre, 1970 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 351)
  - Rotunda Club, 1980 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 352)
  - "The Four Arts", Apr. 1935 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 353)
  - Financial submission to governor, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 354)
  - Financial support, 1935-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 355)
  - Fire regulations and prevention, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 356)
  - Flowers, plants, etc., undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 357)
  - Governor Albertis S. Harrison, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 358)
  - Forms, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 359)
  - John Koenig Memorial, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 360)
  - Overseas travel-Pinkney Near travel requests for summer, travel proposal, breakdown of Trustees special fund, 1959 (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 361)
  - Galleries, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 362)
  - Galleries-security, undated (Box SC-02 Box 8, Folder Folder 363)
  - Correspondence, Forum-House Beautiful: newspaper clippings, photographs, 1945-1948 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 364)
  - World's Fair 1939-Burr Anderson: Richmond Temple article on Virginia Room, photographs, transparency, slide, 1939-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 365)
  - Queens Museum (N.Y.) Gift of Virginia Room plans-blueprint of original design, gift letter, Feb. 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 366)
  - 1939 World's Fair: exhibition catalogue for Carl Milles (1940), newspaper clippings, 1939 World's Fair book and the New York World's Fair 1939/40 photo essay, 1939-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 367)
  - World's Fair and other Special Exhibitions: newspaper clippings regarding N.Y World's Fair, Virginia Room and Brussels World's Fair, 1939-1951 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 368)
  - Virginia Room Article: Mary Tyler Cheek's Virginia Cavalcade article (1985), newspaper clippings, photocopies, budget for Virginia Room and exhibition specifications, 1939-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 369)
  - University of Richmond: 125th Anniversary, 1955 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 370)
  - Newspaper clippings 1956: articles written by and about Leslie Cheek Jr. (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 371)
  - Cheek oral history project, undated (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 372)
  - Oral History Project, Archives of American Art, 1980-1983 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 373)
  - Virginia Museum, 1955-90: VMT 35th anniversary, newspaper clippings, list of season programs, photographs of VMT under construction in 1954 and 1989-1990 MISSING, 1955-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 374)
  - Correspondence with Buck Pennington: preliminary plans, 1983 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 375)
  - General Correspondence: correspondence with Paul Mellon, newspaper clippings and magazine articles, "A Very Private Man And His Supreme Gifts To The Public," John Canaday, Smithsonian Magazine (undated), 1977-1983 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 376)
  - Jackson Monument: newspaper clippings, W&M Fine Arts department, 1939 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 377)
  - Art Commission of Virginia: New York World's Fair, Virginia Room, Jackson Monument review panel of which Cheek was a member, 1938-1939 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 378)
  - Conrad Swan: letter to Col. Fitzroy, 1964 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 379)
  - Christmas Party, 1964 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 380)
  - Director Theatre-Telford: operation and development of VMT to Theatre Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 381)
  - Virginia Museum: service as VMFA consultant and as Director Emeritus, 1968-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 382)
  - Anne Miller-5pm: Miller's thesis topic "Southern Artists", Mar. 1974 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 383)
  - VMFA Consultant 1986: museum events and collection (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 384)
  - VMFA Consultant 1987: museum events and collection, repurchase of Pandora, photographs (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 385)
  - VMFA Consultant 1988: theatre award, museum events and collection (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 386)
  - VMFA Consultant 1989: Senate resolution of Cheek's contributions to the Arts, VMFA long range plans, photographs, original menu from Egyptian Gallery Preview (1961) (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 387)
  - Library-Betty Stacy: gifts to museum library and research questions, 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 388)
  - Collectors' Circle, 1981-1986 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 389)
  - Collectors' Circle-Leslie Cheek membership, 1987-1990 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 390)
  - Paul Perrot-Virginia Museum: historical background for the three large interiors of VMFA, transcript of lecture by John White (1960), 1985-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 391)
  - Museum Director-Paul Perrot: events, 1983-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 392)
  - Virginia Museum 1990: events and Theatre Virginia (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 393)
  - VMFA 1962-correspondence with Basil Taylor, exhibition and program publication for English Art exhibit, "American Painting '62" checklists (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 394)
  - VMFA 1960- "Form Givers" catalogue, season summary and financial statement, 1959-1960 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 395)
  - VMFA miscellaneous-newspaper clippings, history of the museum, minutes of the first Board of Directors of the VMFA, June 23, 1934, newspaper clippings, miscellaneous invitations, 1934-1982 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 396)
  - 16 May '69 Party for Cheeks-dinner honoring Cheek, programs, schedules, new clippings on new wing, 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 397)
  - VMT 1957-drama series layout and publications for museum program, 1957-1958 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 398)
  - Architecture in Virginia by William B. O'Neal-newspaper clippings and correspondence concerning "Architecture in Virginia: An Official Guide to Four Centuries of Building In The Old Dominion", 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 399)